A Guide to the Virginia Room Vertical and Historic Landmark Files, Undated
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Virginia Room Vertical and Historic Landmark Files, Undated
Fairfax County Public Library
40.0 linear feet
The Virginia Room Vertical and Historic Landmark Files consist of over 2,000 files on Fairfax County historical landmarks, communities, buildings, neighborhoods, churches, schools, and general county topics. The files contain newspaper clippings, reports, brochures, photocopies, correspondence, ephemera, and articles.
Virginia Room staff
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection created by Virginia Room staff over a period of years
Historical and Biographical Information
With the establishment of the Virginiana Collection of the Fairfax County Public Library in the mid-1950s, Virginia Room librarians have continuously maintained vertical subject files on Fairfax County’s history and infrastructure. The Virginia Room Vertical and Historic Landmark Files consist of over 2,000 files on Fairfax County historical landmarks, communities, buildings, neighborhoods, churches, schools, and general county topics. The files contain newspaper clippings, reports, brochures, photocopies, correspondence, ephemera, and articles.
Subject files are located in two different file cabinets in the Virginia Room. Files that have an “HLF” prefix are found in the Historic Landmark File cabinets while files with a “VF” are found in the Vertical Files cabinets.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Room Vertical and Historic Landmark Files consist of over 2,000 files containing newspaper clippings, reports, brochures, photocopies, correspondence, ephemera, and articles on Fairfax County’s history and infrastructure.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax County (Va.) - History
Container List
- HLF - Accotink - History
- HLF - Accotink Bluff Estates - (Southampton Station)
- HLF - Accotink Park / Lake Accotink
- VF - Aging
- VF - Agriculture
- HLF - Agriculture - History
- VF - Air Pollution
- VF - Air Transportation - Udvar-Hazy Center
- VF - Airports - Dulles
- VF - Airports - Falls Church Airpark
- VF - Airports - Heliports
- VF - Airports - Hybla Valley/GW Air Junction
- VF - Airports - National
- VF - Airports - Popes Head Road Site - (Proposed)
- VF - Airports - Springfield Airport
- VF - Airports - Washington-Virginia Airport - (Baileys Crossroads)
- VF - Alcohol
- VF - Alcohol - ASAP Program
- HLF - Andalusia
- VF - Animals
- VF - Animals - Animal Shelter
- VF - Animals - Cats
- VF - Animals - Dogs
- VF - Animals - Game Wardens
- VF - Animals - Horses
- VF - Animals - Rabies
- HLF - Annandale - 1950s
- HLF - Annandale - 1960s
- HLF - Annandale - 1970s
- HLF - Annandale - 1980s
- HLF - Annandale - 1990s
- HLF - Annandale - 2000s
- HLF - Annandale - Cannon
- HLF - Annandale - History
- HLF - Annandale - Name
- HLF - Annandale Area - Holmes Run Acres
- HLF - Annandale Community Hall
- HLF - Annandale Community Hall (Annandale, Va.).
- VF - Annexation
- VF - Annexation - Alexandria (1951)
- VF - Annexation - Alexandria (1964-66)
- VF - Annexation - Alexandria (1967-69)
- VF - Annexation - Alexandria (1970-71)
- VF - Annexation - Falls Church
- HLF - Anti-Aircraft AAA Gun Sites
- HLF - Appledore
- VF - Apportionment - Fairfax County - BOS - (1950-1959)
- VF - Apportionment - Fairfax County - BOS - (1960-1969)
- VF - Apportionment - Fairfax County - BOS - (1970-1979)
- VF - Apportionment - Fairfax County - BOS - (1980-1989)
- VF - Apportionment - Fairfax County - BOS - (1990-1999)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - U.S. Congress - (1960-1969)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - U.S. Congress - (1970-1979)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - U.S. Congress - (1980-1989)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - U.S. Congress - (1990-1999)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - General Assembly - (1960-1969)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - General Assembly - (1970-1979)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - General Assembly - (1980-1989)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - General Assembly - (1990-1999)
- VF - Apportionment - Virginia - U.S. Congress - (1930-1939)
- HLF - Arch Hall
- VF - Archeology
- HLF - Arcturus
- VF - Arts - Music
- VF - Arts - Music - Fairfax Symphony Orchestra
- VF - Arts - Music - No. Va. Youth Symphony
- VF - Arts - Music - American Symphony Orchestra League
- VF - Arts & Artists
- HLF - Ash Grove (Vienna, Va.).
- HLF - Ashford - 5318 Guinea Road
- HLF - Ashland
- VF - Authors
- HLF - Avon (Cockerille Home)
- HLF - Bailey Crossroads - Culmore
- HLF - Bailey Crossroads - Payne House
- HLF - Baileys Crossroads - History - (1 of 2)
- HLF - Baileys Crossroads - History - (2 of 2)
- HLF - Baileys Crossroads - History - Battle Hymn of the Republic
- HLF - Baileys Crossroads - History - Skyline Center Collapse
- HLF - Baileys Crossroads - Peace Valley
- HLF - Baileys Skyline Center Collapse
- HLF - Ballantrae
- HLF - Banks
- VF - Banks & Banking
- HLF - Barcroft Mill (Baileys Crossroads, Va.).
- HLF - Barns - History
- HLF - Bayliss House - 9600 Ferry Harbour CT, Alexandria, Va.
- HLF - Bayliss House, David & Elizabeth - 5918 Telegraph RD, Alexandria, Va.
- HLF - Beach House - 7800 Ox RD, Fairfax Station, Va.
- HLF - Beacon Field Airport
- HLF - Beale Treasure - See: Myths & Legends-Beale Treasure
- HLF - Beaufort
- HLF - Bellapais (Alexandria, Va.).
- HLF - Belle Haven Area - History
- HLF - Belmont
- HLF - Belmont Bay Seaport - (Proposed, 1964-1965)
- HLF - Belvale
- HLF - Belvoir (Fort Belvoir, Va.).
- HLF - Bienvenue
- HLF - Black Hill Farm
- HLF - Black History
- HLF - Bloomfield - (See: Holly Knoll)
- HLF - Bolling Field
- HLF - Bonnie Brough
- VF - Boundaries - Fairfax County - (See also Annexation)
- VF - Boundaries - State
- HLF - Boundary Stones
- HLF - Bowman Distillery - (1948-1959) - See also Sunset Hills
- HLF - Bowman Distillery - (1960-1969) - See also Sunset Hills
- HLF - Bowman Distillery - (1970-1979) - See also Sunset Hills
- HLF - Bowman Distillery - (1980-1989) - See also Sunset Hills
- HLF - Bowman Distillery - (1990-1999) - See also Sunset Hills
- HLF - Boxhill Farm
- HLF - Bradley Farm
- HLF - Briarwood
- VF - Bridges
- VF - Bridges - American Legion - (Cabin John)
- VF - Bridges - Chain Bridge
- VF - Bridges - Occoquan
- VF - Bridges - Three Sisters - (Proposed)
- VF - Bridges - Woodrow Wilson
- HLF - Brimstone Hill
- HLF - Brown's Mill
- HLF - Buck Hall
- VF - Budget (1960s)
- VF - Budget (1970s)
- VF - Budget (pre-1960s)
- HLF - Bull Neck Gold Mine
- HLF - Bull Run Power Company
- HLF - Bull Run Stone Bridge
- HLF - Burgundy Farm
- HLF - Burke - Airport
- HLF - Burke - Burke Historical Society
- HLF - Burke - Burke Hotel
- HLF - Burke - Burke House (Silas Burke)
- HLF - Burke - Copperthite Racetrack
- HLF - Burke - Historic Homes
- HLF - Burke - History - Early History
- HLF - Burke - History - 1950s
- HLF - Burke - History - 1960s
- HLF - Burke - History - 1970s
- HLF - Burke - History - 1980s
- HLF - Burke - History - 1990s
- HLF - Burke - History - 2000s
- HLF - Burke - History - Undated
- HLF - Burke - Post Office
- HLF - Burke - Railroad Station
- HLF - Burke Centre - History
- HLF - Burling Tract - See VF: Parks - Fairfax Co. - Scott's Run
- HLF - Burlington
- HLF - Burton-Money House
- HLF - Bush Hill
- HLF - Byrd Mill
- HLF - Cabell's Mill
- HLF - Cabell's Mill Miller's House
- VF - Cable Television - (General, 1982)
- VF - Cable Television - (General, 1983)
- VF - Cable Television - (General, 1984)
- VF - Cable Television - (General, 1985-90)
- VF - Cable Television - (General, pre-1982)
- HLF - Camp Alger, Russell A. - (Spanish-American War)
- HLF - Camp Early
- VF - Camps
- HLF - Carlby
- HLF - Carper House
- HLF - Carrolltown Community
- HLF - Carter House
- HLF - Cedar Grove
- HLF - Cedar Hill
- HLF - Cedar Knoll Inn
- HLF - Cedar Knolls [Subdivision]
- VF - Center for Innovative Technology
- HLF - Central Intelligence Agency
- HLF - Centreville - (1961-1970)
- HLF - Centreville - (1971-1980)
- HLF - Centreville - (1981-1990)
- HLF - Centreville - (1991-2000)
- HLF - Centreville - (2001- )
- HLF - Centreville - Black Hill Farm
- HLF - Centreville - Edward Kersh Home
- HLF - Centreville - Hardee Chambliss' Law Office
- HLF - Centreville - Harrison House and Outbuilding
- HLF - Centreville - Havener House
- HLF - Centreville - Henry Sutphin Farm
- HLF - Centreville - Historic District
- HLF - Centreville - History
- HLF - Centreville - History - Civil War
- HLF - Centreville - History - Bicentennial (1992)
- HLF - Centreville - London Towne Subdivision
- HLF - Centreville - Mary Elizabeth Inn
- HLF - Centreville - Newgate Mall (Proposed)
- HLF - Centreville - Newgate Tavern (Eagle Tavern)
- HLF - Centreville - Paynes Farm
- HLF - Centreville - Paynes Store & Restaurant
- HLF - Centreville - Roads
- HLF - Centreville - Rocky Gorge Development
- HLF - Centreville - Stone House / Filling Station
- HLF - Centreville - Trinity Center
- HLF - Centreville - Utterback (Enos) House
- HLF - Centreville - Westfield Corporate Center
- HLF - Chain Bridge Road (753)
- VF - Chamber of Commerce - (City of Fairfax)
- VF - Chamber of Commerce - (Fairfax County)
- VF - Chamber of Commerce - (Mount Vernon-Lee)
- HLF - Chantilly - History
- HLF - Chantilly - History - Battle of Chantilly (Sept. 1, 1862)
- HLF - Chantilly Plantation Stone House - Ayre House - Chantilly (Va.)
- VF - Chesapeake Bay
- VF - Chesapeake Bay - Environment
- VF - Chesapeake Bay - Fishing
- VF - Chesapeake Bay - Legislation
- HLF - Chesterbrook
- HLF - Chestnut Hill
- VF - Children
- VF - Children - Head Start
- VF - Children - SACC Program
- HLF - Chiles Tract
- HLF - Church Hill
- HLF - Churches - (General)
- HLF - Churches - Accotink Methodist Church - Accotink (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - All Dulles Area Muslim Society Mosque - Sterling (Va.) - Islam
- HLF - Churches - Andrew Chapel Methodist Church - Vienna (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Annandale Methodist Church - Annandale (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Antioch Baptist Church - Fairfax Station (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Antioch Christian Church - Vienna (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Arnon Chapel - Great Falls (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Beth El Hebrew Congregation Synagogue - Alexandria (Va.) - Judaism
- HLF - Churches - Bethel Baptist Church - Great Falls (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Bethlehem Baptist Church - Fairfax (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Bethlehem Baptist Church of Gum Springs - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Beulah Baptist Church - Franconia (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Beulah Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Beulah Methodist - Franconia (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Boulevard Baptist Church - Falls Church
- HLF - Churches - Braddock Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Brown's Chapel (Methodist) - Reston (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Bruen Chapel United Methodist Church - Fairfax (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Buckley's Chapel - Fairfax (Va.) - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Burke Methodist - Burke (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Bush Hill Presbyterian Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Calvary Christian Church - Burke (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Calvary Presbyterian Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Calvary Road Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Cameron Parish - History (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Cartersville Baptist Church - Reston (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Centerpointe Church at Fair Oaks - Fairfax (Va.) - Christian
- HLF - Churches - Centreville Baptist Church - Centreville (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Centreville Methodist Church - Centreville (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Chantilly Bible Church - Herndon (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Charity Baptist Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Chesterbrook Methodist Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Christ the Servant Lutheran Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Christian Fellowship Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Christian Fellowship Church - Ashburn (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints - McLean (Va.) - Mormonism
- HLF - Churches - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints - Annandale (Va.) - Mormonism
- HLF - Churches - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints - Fairfax (Va.) - Mormonism
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Apostles - Fairfax (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Assumption - Vienna (Va.). - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Good Shepherd - (see Calvary Christian Church)
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Good Shepherd U.M.C. - Vienna (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Holy Comforter - Vienna (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Holy Spirit - Annandale (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Church of the Nativity - Burke (Va.). - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - Clark's Chapel - Springifeld (Va.) - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Clifton Baptist - Clifton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Clifton Presbyterian Church - Clifton (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Clifton Primitive Baptist Church - Clifton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Congregation Beth Emeth - Henrdon (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Cranford Memorial Methodist Church & Lewis Chapel - Lorton (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Cub Run Primitive Baptist Church - Centreville (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Culmore United Methodist Church - Falls Church (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Dar Al-Hijrah Mosque - Seven Corners (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Dranesville Church of the Brethren - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Dranesville Methodist Church - Dranesville (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Dulin United Methodist Church - Falls Church (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Dunn Loring Methodist Church - Dunn Loring (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Durga Temple - Fairfax Station (Va.) - Hinduism
- HLF - Churches - Emmaus United Church of Christ - Vienna (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Fair Oaks Community Church of God - Herndon (Va.) - Christian
- HLF - Churches - Fairfax Baptist Temple - Fairfax (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Fairfax Central Baptist Sunday School Union
- HLF - Churches - Fairfax Community Church - Fairfax (Va.) - Christian
- HLF - Churches - Fairfax Unitarian Church - Fairfax (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Alexandria - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Chesterbrook - McLean (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Herndon - Herndon (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Kingstowne - Kingstowne (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Merrifield - Merrifield (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - First Baptist Church of Vienna - Vienna (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Floris Presbyterian Church - Henrdon (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Floris United Methodist Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Frying Pan Baptist Meeting House - Herndon (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Galloway United Methodist Church - Falls Church (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Good Shepherd Catholic Church - Mount Vernon (Va.). - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - Grace Bible Church - Lorton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Groveton Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Harvest Christian Fellowship Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Heritage Fellowship United Church of Christ - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Herndon Congregational Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Herndon United Methodist Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Herndon United Pentecostal Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Holy Transfiguration Melkite Greek Catholic Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Holy Trinity Orthodox Church - Reston (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Hope Lutheran Church - Annandale (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Idylwood Presbyterian Church - Falls Church (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Ilda M. E. Chuch South - Annandale (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Immanuel Bible Church - Springfield (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Immanuel Presbyterian Church - McLean (Va.). - Presbyterian
- HLF - Churches - Jerusalem Baptist Church - Fairfax Station (Va.). - Southern Baptist
- HLF - Churches - King's Chapel - Clifton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Korean Central Presbyterian Church - Centreville (Va.) - Presbyterian
- HLF - Churches - Korean Presbyterian Church of Washington - Fairfax (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Langley Friends Meeting House - Langley (Va.). - Quaker
- HLF - Churches - Laurel Grove Baptist - Franconia (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Lee Chapel - Burke (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Lewinsville Presbyterian Church - McLean (Va.). - Presbyterian
- HLF - Churches - Lincolnia Methodist Church - Alexandria (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Little River United Church of Christ - Annandale (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Little Zion Baptist Church - Burke (Va.). - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Lord of Life Lutheran Church - Clifton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Lutheran Church of the Redeemer - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Martin Luther King Jr. Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - McLean Baptist Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - McLean Bible Church - McLean (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - McLean Presbyterian Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Messiah United Methodist Church - Springfield (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Methodist Episcopal Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Mount Calvary Community Church - Franconia (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Mount Olive Baptist - Centreville (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Mount Pleasant Baptist Church - Herndon (Va.). - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Mount Pleasant Baptist Church - Lincolnia (Va.). - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Mount Vernon Unitarian Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Mount Zoar Baptist Church - Fairfax (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Mubarek Mosque - Chantilly (Va.) - Islam
- HLF - Churches - New Horizons Church of God - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - New Life Christian Church - Chantilly (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - New Union Baptist Church - Vienna (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - New Vision Community Church - Fairfax (Va.) - Presbyterian
- HLF - Churches - Northern Virginia Hebrew Congregation - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Oak Brook Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Oakton Church of the Brethren - Vienna (Va.) - Protestant
- HLF - Churches - Oakton United Methodist Church - Oakton (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Olam Tikvah - Fairfax (Va.) - Jewish
- HLF - Churches - Olivet Episcopal Church - Franconia (Va.). - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - Our Lady of Good Counsel Catholic Church - Vienna (Va.). - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - Ox Hill Baptist Church - Chantilly (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Pender United Methodist Church - Fairfax (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Pleasant Grove Methodist Church - McLean (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Pleasant Valley United Methodist Church - Chantilly (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Plymouth Haven Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Pohick Episcopal Church - Lorton (Va.). - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - Providence Baptist Church - Tysons Corner (Va.). - Southern Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Queen of Apostles Catholic Church - Alexandria (Va.). - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - Rajdhani Mandir Temple - Chantilly (Va.) - Hindu
- HLF - Churches - Redeemer United Methodist Church - Reston (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Reston Baptist Tabernacle - Reston (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Reston Community Catholic Church - Reston (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Reston Community Church - Reston (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Reston Presbyterian Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Rose Hill Baptist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Salem Baptist Church - Great Falls (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Second Baptist Church - Falls Church (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Sharon Chapel / All Saints Episcopal - Franconia (Va.). - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Shiloh Baptist Church - Lorton (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Shiloh Baptist Church - McLean (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Sikh Foundation of Virginia Temple - Fairfax Station (Va.) - Sikh
- HLF - Churches - Silverbrook Methodist - Lorton (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Smith's Chapel United Methodist Church - Great Falls (Va.).
- HLF - Churches - Springfield Christian Church - Springfield (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Springfield United Methodist Church - Springfield (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - St. Ambrose Catholic Church - Annandale - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Andrew Catholic Church - Clifton - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church - Burke (Va.) - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - St. Anne's Episcopal Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - St. Anthony Catholic Church - Falls Church - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Bernadette Catholic Church - Springfield - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Catherine of Sienna Catholic Church - Great Falls - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Christopher's Episcopal Church - Springfield (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - St. Clare of Assissi Catholic Church - Clifton (Va.) - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Francis In-The-Field - Great Falls (Va.) - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - St. George's United Methodist Church - Springfield (Va.) - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - St. James Catholic Church - Falls Church (Va.) - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. John Catholic Church - McLean - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. John Episcopal Church - Centreville - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - St. John Episcopal Church - McLean - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - St. John Neumann Catholic Church - Reston - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Joseph Catholic Church - Herndon - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Joseph Catholic Church - Alexandria (Va.) - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Lawrence Catholic Church - Alexandria - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Louis Catholic Church - Alexandria - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Luke Catholic Church - McLean - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Mark Catholic Church - Vienna - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Mary Catholic Church - Fairfax Station - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Michael Catholic Church - Annandale - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Paul Chung Catholic Church - Fairfax (Va.) - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Paul's Lutheran Church - Falls Church (Va.) - Lutheran
- HLF - Churches - St. Philip Catholic Church - Falls Church - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Raymond Catholic Church - Fairfax Station - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Thomas a Becket Catholic Church - Reston - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Timothy Catholic Church - Centreville - Catholic
- HLF - Churches - St. Timothy Episcopal Church - Herndon - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - Sydenstricker United Methodist Church - Springfield - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Temple Adat Reyim - Springfield (Va.) - Jewish
- HLF - Churches - Temple Baptist Church - Herndon (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Temple B'nai Shalom - Fairfax Station (Va.) - Judaism
- HLF - Churches - Temple Rodef Shalom - Falls Church (Va.) - Jewish
- HLF - Churches - Third Baptist Church - Falls Church (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Trinity United Methodist Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Truro Episcopal Church - Fairfax - Episcopal
- HLF - Churches - Unitarian-Universalist Church (Reston Community) - Reston
- HLF - Churches - United Christian Parish - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Unity of Fairfax Church - Oakton (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Vale Methodist Church - Vale - Methodist
- HLF - Churches - Vienna Dunkard Brethren - Vienna (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Vienna Presbyterian Church - Vienna - Presbyterian
- HLF - Churches - Wakefield Chapel - Annandale
- HLF - Churches - Warner Baptist Church - Lincolnia (Va.). - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Washington Plaza Baptist Church - Reston
- HLF - Churches - Westwood Baptist Church - Springfield (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - William Watters United Methodist Church - McLean (Va.)
- HLF - Churches - Woodlawn Baptist Church - Woodlawn - Baptist
- HLF - Churches - Woodlawn Friends Meeting House - Woodlawn - Quaker
- HLF - Churches - Woodlawn United Methodist Church - Alexandria (Va.)
- HLF - Cityview
- VF - Civil Defense
- HLF - Civil War Earthworks
- HLF - Civilian Conservation Corps
- HLF - Clark House
- HLF - Clark's Crossing Area
- HLF - Claude Moore Colonial Farm - - McLean
- HLF - Cleesh
- HLF - Clermont
- HLF - Clifton - (1960-1965)
- HLF - Clifton - (1966-1970)